（上条(かみじょう)）
ドラマチックかつ
アクロバティックな―
Having spent a dramatic and acrobatic summer vacation,
夏休みを過ごした
わたくし 上条当麻(とうま)が―
I, Kamijyo Touma, obviously had no chance whatsoever to do summer homework.
夏休みの宿題なんていうものに
手をつけてるはずはない
…にもかかわらず
ビリビリの恋人役を演じたり―
Regardless of this fact, I spent the last day pretending to be the Shocker's boyfriend...
魔術師と一戦交えたりするわけだが
...and dueling with a magician.
そんなこと予想もしていなかった
８月31日 午前０時過ぎ
However, completely out of left field was an encounter that took place just past midnight on August 31st.
あいつは
ある出会いを果たしていた
～♪
#19 Last Order
Ending
（不良Ａ）
トリャー！
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
上条ってヤツとの一戦以来―
Since my battle with that Kamijyo guy,
どうやら 俺は学園都市最強では
なくなっちまったらしい
it appears I'm no longer considered the strongest in Academy City.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
俺がレベル５(ファイブ)であることも…
This, despite the fact that I'm still a Level 5...
...and that my powers haven't changed...
能力にも
一切 変わりはないっていうのに
No matter how many times I show them who's boss,
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
何度 証明したって―
these idiots just never learn.
バカどもが この俺に
貼ったレッテルは剥がれねえ
一体…
俺の何が変わったっていうんだ？
What exactly has changed in me?
ハァ…
Something's just different.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
何か違うよな
やっぱ 何かが変わったんだ
Something did change.
でも 何が変わった？
But what?
何なんですか？
What could it be?!
What do you mean you don't feel anything?!
PLACEHOLDER
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
どういうこと？
PLACEHOLDER
Don't you realize that "Hey, she's actually a girl",
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
少しは そういう感情も抱いて…
PLACEHOLDER
that if you don't carry a bit of shame in this act-
Let's bounce the useless noise.
ムダな音は “反射”と
Huh?
はぁ？　何言ってんだ？
この怪人チビ毛布は
What's this hooded, hunchback runt saying?
Oh shoot.
…と いけねえ
"Wow, how should I put it?"
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
いやぁ 何というか―
ここまで完全無反応だと
むしろ すがすがしいというか
"To think you'd have completely no reaction whatsoever, that's actually a really good feeling."
でも 悪意を持って
無視しているにしては―
"But assuming you are malevolently ignoring me, your walking pace is too normal to suggest so."
歩くペースも普通っぽいし
"Conclusion, you must be the ultimate natural person," says MISAKA says MISAKA as she tilts her head.
これは もしかして
究極の天然さんなのかなって―
ミサカはミサカは
首をかしげてみたり
くっだらねえ
Pathetic...
さっきから
ミサカはミサカは自己の存在を―
"MISAKA has MISAKA has been appealing her existence to you continuously for a while now,"
激しくアピールしているのに
存在 全否定？
"yet you completely disregarded it altogether?"
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
待て ミサカだと？
Hold it.
Misaka, you say?
“おお！　ようやくミサカの存在が
認められたよ　わ～い！”って―
"Ohh, so you finally acknowledged MISAKA's existence, woohoo!"
ミサカはミサカは
自画自賛してみたり
as MISAKA self-praises MISAKA self-praises.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
おい
Hey, take off your hood and show your face clearly.
お前 その毛布 取っ払って
よく顔見せてみろ
…て まさか 往来で
女性に服を脱げというのは―
"Huh? Asking a girl to undress in the middle of the road..."
いささか大胆というか
ムチャというか…
"...is quite a daring feat and a reckless demand-"
ウワッ！
Huh?
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
あっ… ウワ～ッ…
ミサカのシリアルナンバーは
20001号で―
"MISAKA's serial number is 20001 and is part of the last lot production of the Sisters,"
妹達(シスターズ)の最終ロットとして
製造されたんだけど
"yet my code is literally 'Last Order'."
コードも まんま
“ラストオーダー”で
実験に
使用されるはずだったんだけどって
"MISAKA was supposed to be used in the 'experiment',"
ミサカはミサカは愚痴ってみたり
grumbles MISAKA grumbles MISAKA.
Oh, is that right?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
ああ そうかい
"Yet the experiment got nulled, and MISAKA got released from the incubation tank in the middle of the process."
ところが 実験が打ち切られて
途中で
培養器から放り出されちゃって
なんだか ちんまりしてるのって
ミサカはミサカは…
"So it seems like the body is quite compact and..." complains MISAKA complains MISAKA-
…て 聞いてるの？
"Hey, are you listening?"
And what do you want from me?
それで俺に
どうしろっていうんだよ？
"You had connections with the scientists,"
あなたは研究者さんとの
つながりもあるから―
コンタクトを
取ってもらえないかなって―
"so could you get in contact with them," thought MISAKA thought MISAKA.
ミサカはミサカは考えるわけ
ほか当たれ
Look somewhere else.
"Yay! Immediate answer, immediate rejection, big fat no!"
イエ～イ！　即答 速攻 大否定！
…て ミサカはミサカは
ヤケクソ気味に叫んでみたり
cries MISAKA cries MISAKA a bit desperately.
"But, there is nowhere else MISAKA can go,"
でも
ほかに行くアテもないので―
ミサカはミサカは
諦められないんだから
as MISAKA as MISAKA doesn't give up hope.
"Please take care of MISAKA~"
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
お世話になりま～すって
ミサカはミサカの先手必勝！
as MISAKA as MISAKA strikes pre-emptively.
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
あなたのお部屋って どこって
ミサカはミサカは質問してみたり
"Where is your room?"
asks MISAKA asks MISAKA.
Room 304.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
304号室
"Coming in!" as MISAKA as MISAKA tries to be polite.
おジャマしま～すって
ミサカはミサカは一応 礼儀なので
（女子生徒）ちょっと なに？
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）あっ…
Excuse me?
全然 違う人の
お部屋だったっぽいんだけどって
"That was completely someone else's room"
as MISAKA as MISAKA shows some indignation.
ミサカはミサカは憤慨してみたり
"This time, tell me the number of the room you live in,"
今度こそ
あなたのお部屋は何号室って―
asks MISAKA asks MISAKA.
ミサカはミサカは聞いてみる
Room 307.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
307号室
"Coming in!"
おジャマしま～す！
（男子生徒）
出前なら頼んでないよ
I didn't order any food.
ウ～ッ… なんで
こんなひどいことするのって―
"Why are you being so mean?"
ミサカはミサカは
肩を落としながら尋ねてみたり
asks MISAKA asks MISAKA while letting her shoulders drop.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
おいおい　何だ こりゃ？
Come on now...
What the hell's this?
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
うわ～！
大変なことになってるって―
"Wow, this is a big mess,"
ミサカはミサカは絶句してみたり
as MISAKA as MISAKA is speechless.
Pathetic.
くっだらねえ
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
え～っと これって警備員(アンチスキル)とか―
"Umm, shouldn't you contact Anti-Skill or Judgment for something like this?"
風紀委員(ジャッジメント)とかに
通報しなくってもいいのって―
as MISAKA as MISAKA suggests unnecessarily.
ミサカはミサカは
要らぬ世話を焼いてみるんだけど
What are you going to do?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
お前は どうすんだ？
It might be safer for you to sleep outside rather than in here.
ここで寝るよりも―
路上で寝泊まりしたほうが
安全かもしれねえぞ
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
う～ん… それでもミサカは
お世話になりたいかなって―
"Even so, MISAKA wants to accept your hospitality,"
ミサカはミサカは頼み込んでみたり
begs MISAKA begs MISAKA.
Huh? Why?
ああ？　なんでだよ？
"Because MISAKA wants to be with someone..."
誰かと一緒にいたいからって
ミサカはミサカは…
says MISAKA says MISAKA...
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
勝手にしろ
Do what you want.
"Just putting this out there... don't try to assault MISAKA in the middle of the night!"
ムッ… 一応 宣告しておくけど―
寝込みを襲うのは
ＮＧなんだからって ミサカは…
says MISAKA-
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）寝ろ！
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）あっ…
Sleep already!
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）ふ～ん…
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）ああ？
人の寝顔って素直な表情に
なるもんどすなって―
"Hmm, people's sleeping expression really shows their true selves"
says MISAKA says MISAKA using a fake Kyoto accent.
ミサカはミサカは
エセ京都弁を使ってみたり
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
ハァ…
You're still here?
お前 まだ いたのか？
"Good morning!"
おはようございます
"Actually, it's already a time in the day to be saying 'good day'."
…てか もう
こんにちはの時間なんだけど
おなかがすいたので 何かご飯を
作ってくれたりすると―
"MISAKA is hungry, so if you could cook something,"
ミサカはミサカは
幸せ指数が30ほどアップしてみたり
"MISAKA's MISAKA's happiness rating would go up by 30."
"Hey, the kitchen's not over there."
…て 台所は
そっちじゃないと思うんだけど
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
俺が そんなことする人間に
見えんのかよ？
Do I look like I'm someone who'd do that?
"And in order to be surprised there,"
そこで意外性を出すために
エプロン装備の―
"MISAKA anticipated a family-friendly Accelerator equipped with an apron-"
家庭的アクセラレータを
期待してたのにって―
fantasizes MISAKA fantasizes MISAKA...
ミサカはミサカはブー垂れてみたり
あっ …て 待って！
"Hey, wait!"
"Is your hair color natural?"
inquires MISAKA inquires MISAKA.
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
あなたの髪の色って天然さん？
ってミサカはミサカは尋ねてみたり
I'm not too sure of the details myself.
俺も詳しいことは
分っかんねえけどよ
The body's pigments are supposed to protect us from UV rays.
体の色素ってのは紫外線から
身を守るためのもんだろうが
I'm deflecting away all superfluous UV rays,
so my body doesn't need any.
俺は余計な紫外線を
全部 反射しているわけだから―
体が色素を
必要としてねえってわけだ
ふ～ん…
一応 理屈とかあったのねって―
"So there was a reason, after all," says MISAKA says MISAKA in a surprised manner.
ミサカはミサカは
びっくりしてみたり
"Which one shall MISAKA order?"
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）やれやれ…
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）どれにしよっかな
Great...
"Pizza, Hamburg steak, spaghetti, or curry?"
ピザにハンバーグにスパゲティ
それとも カレー？
Isn't that... Amai Ao?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
あいつ… 天井亜雄(あまい あお)？
What the hell is that guy doing here?
あの野郎
こんな所で何してやがんだ？
"What are you looking at?" asks MISAKA asks MISAKA.
なに見てるのって
ミサカはミサカは聞いてみたり
Remember your top priority again!
てめえの今いちばんの
目的ってのを思い出してみろ！
えっ？　ご飯食べることだけどって
ミサカはミサカは即答してみたり
"Huh? To eat a meal?" answers MISAKA answers MISAKA immediately.
（店員）
お待たせしました
Here's your order.
温(あった)かいご飯って
これが初めてだったりって―
"This might be the first time MISAKA has had a hot meal,"
as MISAKA as MISAKA cries for joy.
ミサカはミサカは
はしゃいでみたり
くっだらねえ
Pathetic.
どうした？　食わないのか？
What?
You're not going to eat?
いっただきま～すっていうのを
やってみたいって―
"MISAKA wants to try saying 'itadakimasu' once,"
requests MISAKA requests MISAKA.
ミサカはミサカは
希望を言ってみたりして
Yeah? Go ahead.
あっ そう　ご自由に
いっただきま～す！
"Itadakimasu!"
メチャクチャおいしいって
ミサカはミサカは評価してみたり
"It's very delicious!" praises MISAKA praises MISAKA.
Huh?
はぁ？　こんな物(もん)―
This is just a plethora of frozen food.
冷凍とかフリーズドライの
オンパレードじゃねえか
おいしい物は おいしいし
"Delicious food is delicious!"
"And eating a meal with someone else brings a different feeling," as MISAKA as MISAKA suggests a mentality theory.
誰かと食べるご飯って
なんだか感覚が違うって―
ミサカはミサカは
精神論を述べてみたり
What kind of stuff is inside your brain?
お前 どういう神経してんだ？
俺が お前たちに何やったか
知らねえわけじゃねえんだろう？
It's not like you don't know what I did to the rest of you, right?
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
ミサカは全てのミサカと
脳波リンクで つながっているので
"MISAKA is neurally connected to all MISAKA,"
もちろん知ってるって
ミサカはミサカは言ってみる
"so of course MISAKA knows," says MISAKA says MISAKA.
So why can you be so calm in front of me?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
だったら
なんで 平然としてられるんだ？
"MISAKA was taught MISAKA's value by MISAKA," concludes MISAKA concludes MISAKA.
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
ミサカはミサカの価値を
教えてもらったって断言してみる
Huh?
ミサカ単体が死亡しても―
"Even if a single MISAKA dies, there's no way
the entire MISAKA network would disappear."
ミサカネットワークそのものが
消滅することはありえない
"But every single MISAKA's life has its own worth."
だけど ミサカ単体の命にも
価値があるんだって
There's only one of you in this world, isn't there?!
お前は世界で
たったひとりしかいねえだろうが
ミサカが死ぬことで―
"Someone will cry for MISAKA if MISAKA were to die, that was what MISAKA was taught."
涙を流す人もいるんだってことを
教えてもらったから
だから ミサカは もう死なない
"That's why MISAKA will not die anymore."
これ以上は１人だって
死んでやることはできないって―
"None of us are allowed to die anymore," concludes MISAKA concludes MISAKA.
ミサカはミサカは考えてる
フン！
あなたがいなければ
実験が立案されることもなく―
"Without you, the experiment would never have been proposed,"
命なきミサカに魂が
注ぎ込まれることはなかったって
"and souls would never have been 'injected' into lifeless MISAKA," thanks MISAKA thanks MISAKA.
ミサカはミサカは感謝してみる
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
感謝だ？
Thank?
何だよ そりゃ？
俺が お前たちを―
What's with that joke?
It still doesn't change the fact that I took pleasure in giving you Sisters a massacre.
楽しんで殺しまくったってことに
変わりはねえだろうが
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）それはウソ
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）あっ…
"That's a lie,"
opines MISAKA opines MISAKA.
…て
ミサカはミサカは断じてみたり
"You really didn't want to do the experiment," theorizes MISAKA theorizes MISAKA.
あなたは本当は
実験なんてしたくなかったって―
ミサカはミサカは推測してみる
一体 どこを どう美化すりゃ
そんなセリフが出てくるんだよ？
Exactly how do you beautify what happened and come up with that conclusion?!
俺が実験を続けていた以上―
The fact I kept continuing with the experiment meant that I thought nothing of your lives!
お前たちの命なんて
何とも思っていなかった
That's all there is to this.
ただ それだけのことだろうが
"You tried to communicate with MISAKA many times."
あなたは実験のとき
何度もミサカに話しかけている
"What was your objective in that?"
asks MISAKA asks MISAKA rhetorically.
では その目的はって―
ミサカはミサカは
分かりきった質問をしてみる
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
…んだ？　その逃げ腰は
Why're you running?
Flashing your buttocks so joyfully at me like that...
愉快に ケツ振りやがって
誘ってんのか？
You leading me on or something?
まあ 俺が強くなるための実験に
つきあわせてる身で―
Well, you realize I don't really have to confirm anything because it's an experiment that's trying to make me stronger...
言えた義理じゃねえんだけどさ
But you sure look calm knowing your situation...
よく平然としてるよな この状況で
Great.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
…たく ちっとは暇でも
つぶしてみようと考えたんだが
I wanted to kill some time, but that doesn't seem possible.
こりゃダメだな
I can't talk with you at all.
やっぱ お前とは会話になんねえわ
"All of these were strange conversations," analyzes MISAKA analyzes MISAKA.
どれもこれも おかしな会話って
ミサカはミサカは分析してみる
人に話しかけたいという
コミュニケーションの原理は―
"The principle of communication, to talk with someone, is to establish a link with others,"
人と結び付きたい
という理由のためで
ただ 実験を
成功させるためっていうなら―
"and if it were just to make the experiment successful,
then you wouldn't have had a need to engage in a conversation,"
会話する必要はないはずって
ミサカはミサカは論じてみる
theorizes MISAKA theorizes MISAKA.
あの汚ねえ言葉のどこが “人と
結び付きたい”に つながんだよ？
Where do those dirty words say I want to establish a link with others?
そう… そこが
おかしな所の２つ目って―
"Yes, that is the second strange part,"
as MISAKA as MISAKA raises two fingers.
ミサカはミサカは
指を２本立ててみる
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
あなたの言葉は
どれもこれもが徹底して―
"All of your words were unreserved and were all insults on MISAKA."
ミサカを罵倒する言葉ばかり
それだと 人と結び付きたいという
理由から離れてしまう
"That diverges from the reason of wanting to establish a link with others."
だけど もしも仮に―
"But, if one assumes these were words that desired a denial in response..."
否定してほしくて
言っていた言葉だとしたら
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
あなたの言葉は いつだって 実験…
"All of your words were spoken before the experiments..."
つまり
戦闘の前に告げられていたって―
"...in other words, the battles,"
recalls MISAKA recalls MISAKA.
ミサカはミサカは思い出してみる
"As if to scare MISAKA."
まるで
ミサカをおびえさせるように…
"As if to make MISAKA scared so that she won't want to fight anymore," suggests MISAKA suggests MISAKA.
ミサカに もう戦うのはイヤだって
言わせたいようにって―
ミサカはミサカは述べてみる
"All MISAKA were not able to notice your sign."
ミサカたちは あなたのサインに
気づくことができなかった
もし仮に ミサカが
戦いたくないって言っていたら？
"Let's assume MISAKA said she didn't want to fight anymore, what would you do?"
discourses MISAKA discourses MISAKA on a decision in the past.
ミサカはミサカは
終わった選択肢について語ってみる
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
つきあってらんねえ
Enough of this.
Hey.
おい
ミサカは まだ
肉体的に未完成な状態だから―
"MISAKA is still in a condition where her body is incomplete."
"MISAKA should not even be outside the incubation tank, but..."
本来なら 培養器の中から出ちゃ
いけないはずだったんだけどって
as MISAKA as MISAKA lets out a sigh.
ミサカはミサカは
ため息をついてみる
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
今まで なんとかなってたから―
"MISAKA was able to manage thus far and should be fine," thought MISAKA thought MISAKA...
大丈夫かなって
ミサカは ミサカは…
Hey.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
おい
あれ？
どっか行っちゃうのって―
"Are you going away?" inquires MISAKA inquires MISAKA.
ミサカはミサカは尋ねてみる
"There's still some food left on the table."
まだ ご飯残ってるのに…
ああ 食欲なくなっちまった
I don't feel like eating anymore.
"MISAKA sees."
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
そっか…
"MISAKA wanted to say 'thanks for the meal' as well,"
as MISAKA as MISAKA lets out a sigh.
ごちそうさまっていうのも
言ってみたかったって―
ミサカはミサカは
ため息をついてみる
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
そうかよ　そりゃ残念だったな
Yeah?
Too bad.
What the hell am I doing all the way here?
なんだって
こんなとこまで来ちまったんだ？
（ドアの開閉音）
（芳川(よしかわ)）うん？
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）よう
（芳川）あら おかえりなさい
Yo.
Oh, welcome back.
You didn't have to break the door;
your ID card is still in effect for another 90 days.
ドアは壊さなくても 君のＩＤは
まだ90日ほど有効だから
I'd already broken it.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）もう壊しちまったよ
（芳川）そう
Is that so?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
こんな部屋で１日中 データに
うずもれてんのが楽しいのか？
Is drowning yourself in this room with all this data the entire day any fun?
（芳川）
楽しくはないわね
Not at all.
可能なら
君の手も借りたいくらいだわ
If possible, I'd even want your assistance.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
フッ… よせよ
Give it up.
Hey Yoshikawa.
なあ 芳川
Which one of these is the Sisters'
experimental body adjustment manual?
妹達(シスターズ)の検体調整用マニュアルって
どれだ？
And I'm going to borrow one set of adjustment equipment, as well.
あと 調整用の設備も借りるぞ
理由は聞くな
Don't ask the reason.
Just consider this an experimental stipend for me, who never got paid because of the cancellation of the experiment.
実験の凍結で未払いになってる
契約料だと思ってくれりゃいい
How did you find out?
（芳川）
どういうこと？
I only noticed this a few hours ago,
私が気づいたのは数時間前
and I'm still trying to debug the problem inside their personality files.
今も 彼女たちの人格データの中の
バグを洗い出してるところよ
How did you...
（芳川）なぜ それを？
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）ああ？
Huh?
Perhaps, I should call it a virus to be more accurate.
正確には ウイルスと
呼ぶべきかもしれないけど
Hold it.
待て　何言ってんだ？　お前
What are you talking about?
（芳川）
君には説明していなかったわね
I didn't explain this to you, did I?
ラストオーダーと呼ばれる
特別な個体のことは
About the special experimental instance, known as Last Order.
She's... special?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
あいつが 特別？
（芳川）
“あいつ”ね
"She", eh?
She was never made to be part of the experiment to begin with.
そもそも あの子は実験のために
作られたものではないの
They were made to be killed by me, weren't they?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
ヤツらは俺に殺されるために
作られたんじゃなかったのかよ？
Yes.
（芳川）
ええ　でも その実験は―
But how many battles needed to take place for the experiment to finish?
何通りの戦闘を行えば
完了するのだったかしら？
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
２万ジャストだろう　あっ…
Twenty thousand, exact.
"MISAKA's serial number is 20001 and is part of the last lot production of the Sisters,"
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
ミサカのシリアルナンバーは
20001号で―
妹達(シスターズ)の最終ロットとして
製造されたんだけど…
Yes, she is an instance that was not part of the experiment.
（芳川）
そう　あの子は
実験のシナリオには必要のない個体
Last Order is the command center of the MISAKA network.
ラストオーダーは
ミサカネットワークの司令塔
For that purpose, her development was held up intentionally.
そのために あえて
未完成な状態に とどめてある
実験終了後も秘密裏に
預かっていたのだけれど―
We took care of her in secrecy even after the experiment was terminated.
However, someone overwrote her program with malcode.
何者かが あの子の頭に
不正なプログラムを上書きした
The action she took to prevent that was to run away from here.
それを防ごうとした行為が
ここからの逃亡
That happened seven days ago.
それが７日前のこと
（芳川）
こちらで つかんだウイルスの
起動予想時間は―
The virus activation time we found out was tonight, September 1st, 12:00 am.
今晩 ９月１日 午前０時
If the virus is activated
もし 起動が始まれば
ミサカネットワークを介して―
all Sisters will be infected through
the MISAKA network and will go berserk.
全妹達(シスターズ)に感染 暴走
At that point, no one can stop them.
そうなったら 誰も止められないわ
And what's the content of this virus?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
…で そのウイルスの中身は？
恐らく 人間に対する無差別な攻撃
Most likely an indiscriminate attack against all humans.
フッ… 面白(おもしれ)え
Interesting.
Our suspect is a war instigator or weapons supplier?
犯人は戦争屋か 軍需産業か？
Amai Ao.
（芳川）天井亜雄
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）あっ…
Former researcher of the Radio Noise Project.
（芳川）
量産型能力者(レディオノイズ)計画の元研究員
No one is more familiar with the Sisters' personality files than him.
彼以上に 妹達(シスターズ)の
人格データに詳しい者はいない
I just saw him actually.
そいつなら さっき見かけたぜ
Say what?
なんですって？
Anyway, how do we stop the virus inside her brain?
それはそうと あいつの頭ん中の
ウイルスは どうやって止める？
（芳川）
それを今 調べているところよ
That's what I'm investigating now.
でも リミットまでに
解決方法が見つからなければ…
However, if we don't find a resolution by the time limit...
まさか あのガキを…
Are you thinking about...
Yes, we'll need to dispose of her.
そう… 処分するしかないわ
そうならないために努力はしてる
I am doing what I can so that we don't end up doing that.
Of course, you can do something, as well.
もちろん 君にだって何かはできる
フン… 俺は妹達(シスターズ)を
１万人ほど ぶっ殺した張本人だぜ
I'm the guy that butchered 10,000 of those Sisters.
And you're asking that bad guy to save who now?
そんな悪人に誰を救えって？
I shall answer that by saying we're the ones that made you do that.
それを しむけたのは―
私たちだったって
答えさせてもらうわ
If there had been a way of evolving you into a Level 6
without having to use the Sisters,
私たちが妹達(シスターズ)を使わなくても―
レベル６に進化できる方法を
見つけることができていれば―
then you wouldn't have had to kill anyone.
君は誰も殺さずに済んだのだから
そんなひと言だけで
お前を信じて従えって？
You want me to trust and obey you for just that one reason?
やりたくないなら 強制はしない
I won't force you if you don't want to.
今 君にできることは２つ
There are two things you can choose to do now.
One, capture Amai Ao, make him talk about
the virus' structure, and resolve the incident.
ひとつは 天井亜雄を捕らえて―
ウイルスの仕組みを吐かせ
事件を解決すること
Two, secure Last Order, who bears the virus in her right now, and put her back into the incubation tank.
そして もうひとつは
起動前のウイルスを抱えた―
ラストオーダーを保護して
培養器の中に戻すこと
あなたは
両方と面識があるみたいだし―
You seem to have an acquaintance with both targets.
So you don't need any explanation, huh?
説明は要らないわね
The data and files on both of them.
それぞれのデータと資料よ
Pick your poison.
好きなほうを選びなさい
Of course, you're more adept at destroying than protecting.
（芳川）
もっとも 君は守るより
壊すほうが得意でしょうけど
You're right about that.
まあ そうだよな
It's obvious to anyone which one's the right one to pick.
どっち取りゃいいかなんざ
誰でも分かんじゃねえかよ
～♪
Next Episode
（上条）
ウイルス起動まで あと僅か
There's only a little time left before the activation of the virus.
The desperate idea that Accelerator came up with.
アクセラレータの
脳裏に浮かんだ決死の手段
Will a miracle happen for him, who's trying to defy fate?
あくまでも運命にあらがう彼に
奇跡は起きるのか？
次回 「最終信号(ウイルス･コード)」
Next time, "Virus Code".
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる
When science and magic cross paths,
this epic will begin!